Lisa Gallagher

RN

Arlington, TX lisagallagher2004@yahoo.com 210-885-7243

RN with BSN and 25 years acute care experience which has included providing both pre and post operative patient care, med/surg/Tele, IV Therapy, ortho/rehab/SNF, Admit RN, Detox/Behavioral Health, Adult and Pediatric ER, Case Management/Discharge Planning, House Supervisor and have a great deal of experience as a system wide Float Pool RN. I have strong critical thinking and time Management skills. I enjoy exploring many different areas of the nursing field. I also have Charge and Preceptor experience.

Willing to relocate to: Arlington, TX - Fort Worth, TX - Mansfield, TX Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

RN Case Manager PRN

Texas Health Arlington Memorial Hospital - Arlington, TX July 2018 to Present

I hold a PRN RN Case Management position where I only work on an as needed basis to assist in the transitional care & process for inpatients going to their next level of care whether it be to home with home health care and/or DME, outpatient services such as IV Therapy, SNF or Nursing Home placement as well as Hospice or Palliative Care.

RN Charge Nurse Medical Long length of Stay unit (related to underlying Psychiatric illness, Staff RN, Case manager

Providence Medical Center - Everett, WA November 2015 to October 2017

I initially worked as float pool RN on day shift doing direct patient care on busy med/surg & tele units before transferring into a case management RN position where I did discharge planning. I most recently was serving as a night shift charge RN of a medical extended stay unit. (1RN:CNA'S:10patients). These patients were medically stable but held a psychiatric illness preventing them from returning to their prior home situation

RN

Roper St. Francis Healthcare - Charleston, SC January 2015 to September 2015

Employed at night to assigned units between med/surg & stepdown. Responsible to float to both Roper & St. Francis hospitals.

Float Pool RN

Providence Medical Center - Everett, WA January 2013 to October 2014

Serve as float RN at night to assigned units, including med/surg, tele, renal, ortho, rehab, PRN/admit nurse, New admit facilitator, IV therapy team, and post surgical unit at Pacific Campus.

Resource/Float Nurse

Medstar St. Mary's Hospital - Leonardtown, MD November 2011 to December 2012

Served as a float nurse primarily between med/surg and tele units with occasional shifts to task in ER & to be 2nd RN in Behavioral Health. Also cross-trained & did shifts as hospital admit nurse.

Float Pool Nurse

Christus Santa Rosa - San Antonio, TX October 2010 to November 2011

Served as a staff nurse who floats to various units of need to provide direct patient care and develop plans of care based on patient focused problems.

Telemetry Nurse

Shore Health System - Easton, MD July 2009 to March 2011

Served as a staff nurse on night shift providing direct patient care, performing assessments, administering medications and developing patient plans of care.

Telemetry Nurse, Float Pool

Christus Santa Rosa - San Antonio, TX February 2009 to July 2009

Served as a staff nurse on various units & hospitals of need within the Christus system. Perform assessments, administer medications, develop plans of care and assist physicians with bedside procedures.

Telemetry Nurse

Shore Health System - Easton, MD July 2008 to January 2009

Med/Surg/Telemetry Float Nurse

Access Nurses Inc - San Antonio, TX January 2007 to June 2008

Provided healthcare as a staff nurse to inpatient population with cardiac needs.

Christus Santa Rosa San Antonio, TX
Med/Surg/Telemetry Float Nurse Jan. 2007-June 2008
Served as a staff float nurse between facilities and units of need.
Provided healthcare to a wide range of patients with medical and surgical diagnoses.

Burn Stepdown Nurse

Brook Army Medical Center - San Antonio, TX December 2004 to October 2006

Served as a contract staff and charge nurse through Spectrum Healthcare Resources at The Institute of Surgical Research, world renowned inpatient burn center.

Provided intense pain management, medical and wound care to severely injured soldiers and civilians. Performed individual recoveries.

Staff & Charge Nurse

Baptist Health System - San Antonio, TX December 2002 to May 2005

Served as a staff nurse. New nurse preceptor, unit charge nurse on a fast paced med/surg unit. Assisted in overseeing the patient care provided by all staff.

Staff & Charge Nurse

Corpus Christi Medical Center - Corpus Christi, TX February 1998 to August 2002

Provided direct patient care, served as physician liason, new nurse preceptor and unit charge nurse before becoming nursing house supervisor.

Pediatric ER Staff Nurse

Driscoll Childrens Hospital - Corpus Christi, TX September 1997 to February 1998

Provided emergency room care to the pediatric patient population

Charge Nurse & Shift Supervisor

Horizon Specialty Hospital - Corpus Christi, TX June 1996 to September 1997

Responsible to oversee entire nursing staff, admit patients & provide routine nursing care to an adult patient population. Served as a physician liason.

Staff Nurse Urology & Adult ER

Christus Spohn Hospital Shoreline - Corpus Christi, TX March 1994 to June 1996

Provided nursing care to post surgical urology patients before transferring to ER

Staff Nurse Med/Surg

Kleberg Memorial Hospital - Kingsville, TX January 1994 to March 1994

Provided inpatient nursing care to patients with a variety of diagnoses

Staff Nurse Med/Surg

Carleton Memorial Hospital May 1993 to December 1993

Provided inpatient nursing care to patients on Med/surg units & in ER, assisted with outpatient endoscopies.

Patient Care Assistant

Pine Grove Nursing Home June 1991 to April 1993

Provided assistive care to long term patients while attending university for my nursing degree

Education

Bachelor of Nursing Degree in Nursing

University of New Brunswick - Fredericton, NB Canada September 1989 to May 1993

Bachelor of Nursing

University of New Brunswick 1993

Nursing Licenses

RN

Expires: June 2019

State: TX

RN

Expires: June 2018

State: WA

Skills

Proficient in multiple tasks & time management. Experienced in providing direct patient care to a multitude of service areas, including post operative care & geriatric/psychiatric patient care, RN, Staff Nurse, CNA, Care Management, Case Management, Hospital

Certifications

BLS/CPR

November 2016 to November 2018

Additional Information

Skills and Qualifications

Telemetry\EKG Certified, IV therapy

Proficient in the use of various hospital equipment such as; IV, PCA, epidural and feeding pumps, cardiac monitoring & non-titrated cardiac drips, suction set-up and performance, traction set-up, and CPM machines.

Experienced in maintaining aseptic technique and sterile environment during simple to complex dressing changes.

Familiar with various hospital computer programs such as Epic, McKesson, Meditech, Novell, HBOC and STAR.

Expert at preparing patients for procedures & surgeries as well as providing post op care.

Highly proficient with the insertion of peripheral intravenous catheters as well as the care and maintenance of central venous catheters and ports.

Safely administer medications, blood and blood products.

Proficient in the development, execution and modification of the patient's care plan.

Involved in the ongoing patient teaching and discharge planning for follow-up care and use of available community resources.

Demonstrate excellent time management and organizational skills with an emphasis on prioritization and appropriate task delegation.

Take pride in helping other nurses and sharing my knowledge base.

Adhere to hospital budget guidelines to achieve cost effectiveness while maintaining patient safety.

Demonstrate excellent communication and interpersonal skills with an energetic and positive attitude.